<TEI xml:id="oeAllenBio" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Biography of Young J. Allen, <date>date unknown</date>, an electronic edition</title>
    <author>
      <name type="person">
        <choice>
          <reg>Jarrell, Charles Crawford, 1874-1961.</reg>
          <sic>Charles Jarrell</sic>
        </choice>
      </name>
    </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Biography of Young J. Allen, Jarrell428, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
    of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
    Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Jarrell, Charles Crawford, 1874-1961.</item>
            <item>Allen, Young John, 1836-1907.</item>
            <item>Education--United States--History--20th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
         </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>Oct 29, 2008</date>  
          <name>Carson Mayberry</name> and <name>Bea Osme&#x00F1;a</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document. 
      </change>
<change>On May 1, 2009 <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>

<text>
<body>
<div>
<pb facs="Allen_Bio_1.jpg"/>
<head> [Biography of Young J. Allen]</head>
<opener/>
<p>Young J. Allen belongs to this remarkable group
of young Georgians destined to great service. He belongs
to Oxford by reason of his student days; and by
reason of his repeated visits to his homeland, when Oxford was always included in
his itinerary. His mighty personality was impressed on town and college in sermons
and addresses, and always as Christ's Ambassador to China. On one of those visits he
honored me with a good long talk,
as he invited me to walk with him under the old trees which had sheltered him
as a college-boy. <del rend="strikethrough">in the Ante-Bellum days</del>
It is not extravagant to call him a colossal
figure in the history of modern missions.</p>

<p>He was converted while a young
student in a school near Starrsville, GA.
He exerted a deep religious influence
over his fellow-students and we find
him leading a daily prayer meeting
for them at the "old log" during one
of the historic revivals that visited the
town in those days. He graduated young
but was mature beyond his years. He soon
married, sold his plantation and slaves,
offered himself to the Board of Missions
<pb facs="Allen_Bio_2.jpg"/>
and was accepted for China.</p>

<p>He had scarcely laid out his work
in and around Shanghai when the "War
Between the States" broke out in his homeland. He was entirely cut off from home
and forced to take a place as teacher and
translator for the Chinese Government, in
order to maintain his family and carry
on his missionary activity. He held the
Mission together until the Church of home
was able to resume its conduct and support,
he then resigned from the Government service
and devoted all his time for the rest of his life to his work as a missionary.</p>
<p>I have heard him say that he considered
himself as a missionary to the whole nation and
to the entire body of the Chinese people. He fitted
himself to be just that. And because China
was a land of many spoken dialects and
because it was also a land of one literary
language, he realized that for his task the
pen must become his instrument of
service.</p>

<p>The output of his busy pen would
comprise a library of nearly 250 volumes--
many of which were translations. <ref target="Allen_Bio.n1">1.</ref>
<note xml:id="Allen_Bio.n1" n="1">Life of Young Allen: By Bishop Warren A. Candler page 150.</note>
<pb facs="Allen_Bio_3.jpg"/>
He founded the "Review of <del rend="strikethough">Missions</del> the Times" and
edited it for more than thirty years. I once
heard him forecasting one of his major literary
projects. He wanted to show the Chinese
people that the key to any civilization
is to be found in the estimate it
places on womanhood. He carried out
that purpose; his monumental
work "Women In All Lands" ran to twenty-one volumes. His "War Between China And
Japan" ran to sixteen volumes. At a
memorial service held for Dr. Allen in
Shanghai, the Chinese presiding officer
said: "While some missionaries worked
only in one city or one church, Dr
Allen through his writings was a missionary to an empire; not only to one,
but to three--China, Japan and Korea.
He reached emperors, empresses, princes,
princesses, viceroys, governors, mayors,
generals, the literate, and the common
people." "In the last decade of the
last decade of the last century Lin Le
Chih (Young J. Allen) was probably
more widely known than any (other)
foreigner who has ever been to China".<ref target="Allen_Bio.n2">1.</ref>
<note xml:id="Allen_Bio.n2" n="1">Life of Young Allen: Candler pgs. 213, 214, 215,</note></p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>