<TEI xml:id="Bryan148-1911-03-19" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter from Lyle Bryan to his mother, March 19, 1911, <date when="1911-03-19">March 3, 1911</date>, an electronic edition</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Bryan, William Lyle, 1890-1960</reg>
	      <sic>Lyle Bryan</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Letter from Lyle Bryan to his mother, March 19, 1911, Bryan148, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1900-1999</date>
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Education--United States--History--20th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date when="2008-10-29">October 29, 2008</date>   
          <name>Ahley Moore></name> and <name>Jasmine Ruffin</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
      <change>On <date when="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding, and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>




<text>
<body>
<pb facs="1911-03-19_1.jpg"/>
<div>
<head>[Letter from Lyle Bryan to his mother, March 19, 1911]</head>
<opener>
<dateline>
<placeName>Oxford, Ga
</placeName> <date when="1911-3-19">March 19, 1911</date></dateline>

<salute>Dear Mother,</salute></opener>	
<p>I suppose you will be glad to learn that I am back at my normal state. My eyes have completely cleared of their redness and are all right except a little weak after their trouble.  They are getting stronger every day and I don't think <pb facs="1911-03-19_2.jpg"/>there is much danger of my having to wear glasses.</p>

<p>I certainly wish I could be at home during Mrs. Calhoun's house party as I would enjoy myself.  I need to mix with people.  I am going to practice for basball next summer and try for the team when I come back my senior year.  I wished I had tried my freshman year I would stand so much better with the boys.  I want Walker to run the relay play baseball and do all athletic stunts he can.  There is something else in college life besides marks and that something I have missed to a large degree.  I am finding it a hard row to try for a "suma". <pb facs="1911-03-19_3.jpg"/>I made a mistake that a fellow don't need many friends and tried to live to myself but this year I have been trying to become more popular.</p>
	
<p>The student body has gotten up a new system of government.  They are to have a student body government and have a president and every thing done by committees.</p>
<p>I don't know how it will <pb facs="1911-03-19_4.jpg"/>work.  The elections will come off on May the first.  The Phoenix officers are going to be elected by the student body at large.  I am anxious to get into the politics and be a leader of men.  I crave power.  If Walker is not afraid to talk at places let him talk.  I have stood back and kept still and others of less compatibilities are getting the plums and <pb facs="1911-03-19_5.jpg"/>it has got to stop.  I am going to have me a good office by next year or I am much mistaken.  I have worked hard to boost others by my shoulders and its fair time to turn.  I don't mean to brag but if it had been my ingenuity Pittman would never have been <unclear>dux</unclear>.  I am going to use that same degree of skill to laud what I want in politics that I have used to lead my class in marks.  Sometimes I get so wrapped up in ambition I can't hardly sit still.  I just feel I have got to do something.  I am getting the "suma" in good shape now and only behind .6 of my point which I believe I can pull up in the spring <pb facs="1911-03-19_6.jpg"/>so I think I will have more time for other things.  Boys like a fellow better who takes more interest in their sports and now that I have time I want to do it.  At present our team is very weak in baseball players and I believe I can make the team next year if I will try next year.</p>
<pb facs="1911-03-19_6.jpg"/>	
<p>Don't feel alarmed at the above. It is first the bubbling over of a youth full of spirits and wanting to succeed and nothing very serious is the matter.
</p>
<closer>
<salute>Goodbye,<lb/> Your loving son,<lb/></salute>
<signed>Lyle Bryan</signed>
</closer>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>


