<TEI xml:id="oeBryan_Letter1909-09-19.9999" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter from Lyle Bryan to his Mother, <date when="1909-09-19">September 9, 1909</date>, an electronic edition</title>
<author><name type="person"><choice><reg>Bryan, William Lyle</reg><sic>Lyle Bryan</sic></choice></name></author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
         <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Erika Farr</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Letter from Lyle Bryan to his mother, September 19, 1909; Lyle Bryan letters, Archive, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1900-1999</date>
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
       On <date>2007-11-12</date>
      
          <name>Allison Harper, </name>
          <name>Kate Hutchinson </name>
          
       
        inserted XML tags in compliance with TEI guidelines.
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>

<text>
<body>
<div type = "letter">
<pb facs="1909-09019_p1.jpg"/>
<head>[Letter from Lyle Bryan to his Mother, September 19, 1909]</head>
<opener>
<dateline>
<date when = "1909-09-19"> 09/19/1909 </date>
<name type = "place"> Oxford, GA </name>
</dateline> 
<salute> Dear <name type="person">Mother</name>, </salute>
</opener>

<p> I suppose you will be interested first to learn of my room.  I bought the rocker, blankets and counter pin in <name type = "place"> Atlanta </name> and had them shipped down.  The freight was only 25 &#x00A2;.  These things with my rugs indeed do make my room cozy.  I bought me a nickel lamp for $2.00.  The counter pin was a good wide one and nicely covers my bed. </p>

	<p>I am rooming by myself.  I had a roommate <pb facs="1909-09019_p2.jpg"/>for about two days.  The first fellow that was sent me was rather seedy looking and I told him to move on.  Then another one came and as he was a sophomore and was neat and clean looking I took him in,  He was from <name type="place"> Tallahassee, Florida </name>.  He stayed here two days and then told me that he believed he would go home as he couldn't stand the fare at the hall so he had his trunk hauled over to <name type = "place"> Covington </name> but the next thing I saw was my dearly beloved coming back.  He had decided he would stay at <pb facs="1909-09019_p3.jpg"/><name> Mrs. Wynn's</name> place.  So now I am by myself. </p>

	<p>There will and increased enrollment this year nearly 300.  We have seventy in our class and there are one hundred freshmen.  There are lots of the back and rafts of new fellows.  I now understand how it is that the old men do not feel towards a new man like they do towards one that they have already known.  <name>Strange</name> <name>White</name> and <name>Sappington</name> are all back.  But what do you think get ready for exclamation!  <name>Bishop</name> is back and is as full of uninvited philosophy as ever.  </p>
<pb facs="1909-09019_p4.jpg"/>
<p>I have been working on my debate a little.  <name>Dr. Turner </name> took my certificate all right it is certainly different from last year this being a sophomore.  Last year when we went to get our cards signed up it was 'get in line there you Freshmen'.  Now the Profs. shake hands with a fellow and say 'I am so glad to see you back.' </p> <name>Wilcox</name> did not come back. I don't know whom we will get for <unclear>dux</unclear>.

	<p>I am study in Latin, Tactitus Agricola.., Trigonometry, History Physics, Mechanics, English Literature, Bible. <pb facs="1909-09019_p5.jpg"/>Every fellow here is going to be measured then see if he develops any during the year.  They take fifty seven measurements on your body.</p>

<p><name>Thrasher</name> and <name>Ashford</name> are back.  They are taking a <hi rend="underline">special</hi>.</p>
	<p>I enclose a piece about <name>Cook</name> that I cut upon the constitution which I thought probably you would enjoy if you had not seen it. </p>
	<p>Write soon to</p>
		<closer>
			 <salute> Your loving son, </salute>
				<signed> <name>Lyle Bryan. </name> </signed>
 </closer>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>