<TEI xml:id="oeCarmichael132" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Junior Adieu to the Class Of '97, <date when="1897">1897</date>, an electronic edition</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Carmichael, Marion Walter, 1870-1935.</reg>
	      <sic>Marion W. Carmichael</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Junior Class of '97, Carmichael 132, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Education--United States--History--19th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>10/29/08</date>   
          <name>Ben Schwartz</name> and <name>Patrick Hart</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
      <change>On <date when="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding, and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div type="speech" xml:id="Carmichael.003">
<pb facs="1897-Class_Adieu_1.jpg"/>
<head>Junior Adieu to the Class Of '97</head>

       <p>Mr. President, Gentlemen of the Senior Class, Ladies and Gentlemen:
This is a time looked forward to with great interest in the history of every class. To many of us it brings a degree of sadness, while to others a heart full of mingled joys. It awakens sweet memories of our associations and relationships here during these years that shall ever be cherished with the tenderest affections. And were we to look back upon the events which have gone to make our history during these short years we would see some that would cause us to regret, but a great many more would give us pleasure and inspiration to press forward to ever greater achievements.</p>
	<p>Gentlemen of the Senior Class, we are about to bid you adieu. Soon these places that are familiar with your presence will know you no more. These shaded walks which you have so frequently trod will soon cease to echo your footsteps. These <pb facs="1897-Class_Adieu_2.jpg"/>classrooms to which you have resorted to drink from the fountain of knowledge soon you will vacate. The wise councils of your instructors to which you have ever listened with the greatest attention you will soon step out into the busy world to prove. And this old Hall which has been made to wring with your eloquences you will leave to enter the stern realities of the forum, the bar, and the pulpit.</p>	<p>It is natural on this occasion that we should give reflection for a moment to our associations here since the days of Fresh and Seldom. Far would I be from saying that it has been otherwise than the most pleasant. On the campus your conduct has ever been courteous; on the diamond and <unclear>gridioron</unclear> you have stood at the head; and here your untiring effort and glorious achievements are worthy the imitation of every one. Not from the beginning of Freshman to the end of Senior is there known a parallel to your loyalty to Old Phi Gamma.</p>
<pb facs="1897-Class_Adieu_3.jpg"/>
	<p>Gentlemen, you leave your <hi rend="underline">Alma Mater</hi> just as she enters upon her most progressive era. You have seen her faculty increased. You have seen her Endowment and Loan Funds augmented, (to which, it pleases me to say, you yourselves have contributed most liberally). And the perpetual stroke of the mechanics hammers tells you that within a few weeks a most magnificent Library Building will stand to adown the already beautiful old campus.</p>
	<p>"There is something solemn and awful in the thought that there is not an act nor thought in the life of a human being but carries with it a train of consequences, the end of which we may never trace."</p>
	<p>Gentlemen, you are soon to enter the arena of busy life, and we would bid you ever remember the preceding quotation. You shall most surely have an influence upon the world. Shall it be for good, or shall it be for evil? This question I have no doubt each of you have already  <pb facs="1897-Class_Adieu_4.jpg"/>considered, and your conduct while connected with this institution warrants us in believing that you have determined for the right.</p> 
	<p>The mantle which you have so successfully worn now falls to us. And in taking it up, we assure you that no pain nor labor shall be spared in our effort to bear it so favorably and honorably as you. Profiting by your fair example we shall strive to add another golden star to Old Phi Gamma's brilliant banner of success.</p>
	<p>Now in behalf of the Junior Class I reluctantly bid you adieu. And as you enter the field of active life may Heavens richest blessings ever be showered upon you.</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

