<TEI xml:id="oe1907song3" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">  <teiHeader id="carmichael1321201">    <fileDesc>      <titleStmt>        <title>Second Song, an electronic edition</title><author><name type="person" reg="">Marion Walter Carmichael</name></author>      </titleStmt>      <extent>10kb</extent>      <publicationStmt>        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>        <date>2007</date>        <availability>          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original contributions made by the Women's Genre Fiction Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>        </availability>      </publicationStmt>      <seriesStmt>        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>        <respStmt>          <name>Christine Loflin</name>          <name>Erika Farr</name>          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>        </respStmt>      </seriesStmt>      <sourceDesc>        <bibl><author></author>. <title></title>. <pubPlace></pubPlace>:<publisher></publisher>, <date></date>.</bibl>      </sourceDesc>    </fileDesc>    <encodingDesc>      <projectDesc>        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>      </projectDesc>      <samplingDecl>        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>      </samplingDecl>      <editorialDecl>        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF imagesof each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were captured in color at 300dpi.  Thesedigital images were converted to an electronic text file bytranscription.  The text files produced have been proofread againstthe original document or a JPEGimage of the original.  This proofread text file has then beenencoded using the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in LibrariesGuidelines.  For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see thewebpage for TEI Guidelines for Best Encoding practices athttp://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.   Encoders silently replaced emdashes with two dashes.  Page numbers displayed in brackets have beenadded by the encoder and do not appear in the original text.</p>      </editorialDecl>      <classDecl>        <taxonomy id="lcsh">          <bibl>            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>          </bibl>        </taxonomy>      </classDecl>    </encodingDesc>    <profileDesc>      <creation>        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>        <rs type="language">English</rs>        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>        <rs type="genre"></rs>        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->      </creation>      <textClass>        <keywords scheme="lcsh">          <list>            <item></item>            <item></item>            <item></item>            <item></item>            <item></item>          </list>        </keywords>      </textClass>    </profileDesc>    <revisionDesc>      <change>        <date>2007-June-26</date>        <respStmt>          <name>Alice Hickcox, </name>          <resp>Electronic Text Specialist.</resp>        </respStmt>	<item>Text transcribed from image of original        XML tags inserted in compliance with TEI guidelines.</item>      </change>    </revisionDesc>  </teiHeader><text><front><!-- critical introduction goes here --></front><body><div type="song"><head>Second Song</head><lg type="stanza"><l>Ring, Ring, ring, ring oh ye bells in gladness</l><l>Sing boys, sing, sing and be happy today--</l><l>Vanish ills, vanish ye visions of sadness</l><l>Joy must reign when trials have passed away</l><l rend="indent">Brighter the sun shines</l><l rend="indent">Closer the vine twines</l><l>Round the oak that would its mother be</l><l rend="indent">Whether the days clear</l><l rend="indent">Whether the days drear</l><l>Shall we fondly cling to Emory.</l></lg><lg><head>Chorus</head><l>March on--we are comrades, happy comrades</l><l>Ninety eight with her banner flowing bright</l><l rend="indent">(Then let us all together)</l><l>Join the fray (e'en today) happy hearted, never parted;</l><l>This our cry, battle cry, "hail to Emory and right.</l></lg><lg><head>(2)</head><l>When the night smiles on the army around us,</l><l>When the stars light the bivouac of the brave,</l><l>Though the foes multiply, thousands surround us.</l><l>Shall we singing never become his slaves,</l><l rend="indent">Be the war gory</l><l rend="indent">Shall we in Story</l><l>Live again the dead &#x0026; <choice><sic>burried</sic><corr>buried</corr></choice> past</l><l rend="indent">Moments of pleasure--</l><l rend="indent">Richly we'll treasure</l><l>Till Death's bugle blows for taps its blast.</l></lg></div></body></text></TEI>