<TEI xml:id="oeJarrell428EmoryCreed" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Emory's Creed, an electronic edition</title>
<author><name type="person"><choice><reg>Jarrell, Charles Crawford, 1874-1961</reg><sic>Charles Crawford Jarrell</sic></choice></name></author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>"Emory's Creed" Speech; Charles Crawford Jarrell Papers, Manuscript, Archive, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
<taxonomy xml:id="MARBL">
<bibl>
<title>MARBL Subjuct Headings</title>
</bibl>
</taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Education--United States--History</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
<keywords scheme="MARBL">
<list>
<item>Emory College--History.</item>
<item>Emory College--Students.</item>
</list>
</keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
<name>Siobhain Rivera, </name>XML tags inserted in compliance with TEI guidelines. <date when="2007-07-18">July 18, 2007</date>
       </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<front><!-- Critical Introduction goes here! --></front>
<body>
<div type="creed">
<pb facs="Jarrell428-EmorysCreed.jpg"/>
<head>Emory's Creed.</head>
<p>Emory stands for something.  A University ought to stand for something besides learning.  Emory has a policy and it has a purpose.  It has a mission and it intends to be true to itself and to its mission.  It stands for the plain and simple things of human life.  It stands for the plain and simple things of human character.  It stands for the plain and simple things of the Christian religion.  It stands for life and that more abundantly; for truth and that freely; for play and that gladly; for faith and that simply; for the best in life, and it believes the best is yet to be.</p>   
<p>It believes in preparation for life and that thoroughly.  It believes in thrift and property, and that it is as necessary for the University to live within its income as it is for the individual or the state, and equally a matter of common honesty as well as good business.  It believes in things of the body, in health, exercise and recreation.  It believes in athletics for all rather than the prowess of the few and the applause of the extra-mural</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
