<TEI xml:id="oeBryan148-1909-05-17" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>
Letter from Lyle Bryan to his mother,  <date when="1909-05-17">May 17, 1909,</date>, an electronic edition
</title>
<author>
<name type="person">
<choice>
<reg>Bryan, William Lyle, 1890-1960</reg>
<sic>N. Lyle Bryan</sic>
</choice>
</name>
</author>
</titleStmt>
<extent/>
<publicationStmt>
<publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
<pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
<date>2007</date>
<availability>
<p>
© 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address>
<addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine>
<addrLine>Emory University</addrLine>
<addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine>
<addrLine>United States of America</addrLine>
<addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
<seriesStmt>
<title>The Oxford Experience</title>
<respStmt>
<name>Christine Loflin</name>
<name>Adriane Ivey</name>
<resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
</respStmt>
</seriesStmt>
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
Letter from Lyle bryan to his mother, May 17, 1909, Bryan 148, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
<encodingDesc>
<projectDesc>
<p>
This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.
</p>
</projectDesc>
<samplingDecl>
<p>
The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.
</p>
</samplingDecl>
<editorialDecl>
<p>
Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.
</p>
</editorialDecl>
<classDecl>
<taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
<bibl>
<title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
</bibl>
</taxonomy>
</classDecl>
</encodingDesc>
<profileDesc>
<creation>
<rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
<rs type="language">English</rs>
<rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
<rs type="form">Edited</rs>
<rs type="genre"/>
<rs type="geography">United States</rs>
<date>1800-1899</date>
<!-- or 1900-1999 -->
</creation>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="lcsh">
<list>
            <item>Education--United States--History--19th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
</list>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>
<revisionDesc>
<change>
On 
<date>2008-10-27</date>
<name>Alex Fung</name>
 and 
<name>Ludia Chang</name>

        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      
</change>
<change>On May 7, 2009 <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding and added subject headings.</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<pb facs="1909-05-17_1.jpg"/>
<div>
<head>
[Letter from Lyle bryan to his mother, May 17, 1909]
</head>
<opener>
<dateline>
<placeName>Oxford, GA</placeName>
<date when="1909-05-17">May 17, 1909</date>
</dateline>
<salute>Dear Mamma,</salute>
</opener>
<p>It is real rainy outside today and I am sitting in my room. The time is 
<choice>
<sic>mearly</sic>
<corr>nearly</corr>
</choice>
here for the final examinations which begin May 25:
 I hope I will make it alright with a fine mark. I think I will be at my mark of least fall a good deal as I am in better fix for the examinations than I was last fall.
</p>
<p><l>“Examination days are here,</l><l> the saddest of the year,</l><l>Busted Sophs and angry Profs.</l><l>And freshmen full of fear.” </l>
</p>
<p>Last night I was up till midnight writing latin prose for Dr. Turner. He forgot to give us any prose last week but this week he gave double so I really have to prepare these lessons for him for Tuesday: two in prose and one in the text. <pb facs="1909-05-17_2.jpg"/>I got the composition from you alright. Thank you for correcting it. I have gotten (E) on every compostion so far. I have raised my grade so far then.
</p>
<p>The boys played a good joke on Prof. Peed the other day. They locked his door and plugged up the keyhole. He had to keep us waiting till he went and got the plug out. Last year the Seniors played a joke on him after this fashion: The Freshmen were in the hall and had been raising a good deal of racket in the lobby and when the senior class went to leave they made out as if they could not open the door as if the Freshmen outside had hold of it. Some of the seniors pulled as hard as they could and others grabbed them around their waist and then all pulled a feint pull. Prof. Peed came up right quick and told his boys to let him have it. He sit back and pulled and bang! It came open for noboby had a hold of it.
</p>
<p>We have a lady visiting here, <pb facs="1909-05-17_3.jpg"/>Mrs. Lowery’s niece and named Miss Anderson. It was a good joke on Thrasher for he got up so late for breakfast that he didn’t put on any sox and wore his night shirt with a tie! And it fell to his lot sit next the lady visitor.
</p>
<p>There will be a real laughable game of baseball which will come off Wednesday evening after the exams close. For the game will be played between a team of the Faculty and a team picked up out of the Senior class consisting of those who have not played on the regular team. I am going to it and “holler” for the seniors and “gye” the faculty.			
</p>
<p>I went to Mrs. Starr’s and had a real nice time, but had the misfortune to sit down under a Japanese lantern and let it drip down all over my coat. What will take tallow out of cloth?		
</p>
<p>Have you told Walker that you were going to let him come down here <pb facs="1909-05-17_4.jpg"/>commencement.
</p>
<p>What do you think of this question? Do you think that to win cum summa laude it worth it to relinquish all hopes of debating honors athletic honors and confine oneself to that one pursuit? I contend that it is and I believe that I would make nearly any sacrifice to get it and be the fourth man to ever make it, but lots of the boys say that it is better to make a lower grade and take part ineverything. I have come nearly at the parting of the ways. My ambition, love of honor, pride, tell me to sacrifice all and make first honor while the boys say to be more of <choice><sic>and</sic><corr>an</corr></choice> all round man. But I believe that there is nothing to equal the ideal of graduating with C.S.L. written on your diploma and to have all the under classmen during your senior year to look on you as one grand.
</p>
<closer>
<salute>Your son</salute>
<signed>W. Lyle Bryan</signed>
</closer>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>