<TEI xml:id="oeWren1858-03" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary of George Lovick Pierce Wren, <date when="1858-03"> March 1858</date>, an electronic edition</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Wren, George Lovick Pierce, 1836-1916.</reg>
	      <sic>George Lovick Pierce Wren</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Diary of George Lovick Pierce Wren, Wren249, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Education--United States--History--19th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>October 29, 2008</date>   
          <name>Meredith Russell</name> and <name>Leah Shapiro</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>      
      <change>On <date when="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding, and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div>
<pb facs="1858-03-30_1-1.jpg"/>
<milestone unit="page" facs="1858-03-30_2-1.jpg" edition="handwritten"/>
<head> [Diary of George Lovick Pierce Wren, <lb/>
March 1858]</head>
<p><date when="1858-03-03">Wednesday 3rd (March, 1858)</date></p>
<p>I think I have almost lost a day for I don't remember scarcely anything that I have gained.  After listening to Prof. Stone's lecture this morning I don't remember but one point in it, and that was about Lazy Lawrence or a tremulous motion that is sometimes seen a few feet above the earth's surface which is caused by the <sic corr="collision">colision</sic> of the atmosphere of different densities. (?)  I have been reading tonight but not to much effect as my mind don't seem to be in a good plight for understanding, but it seems to be in a sort of a mathematical plight as I have worked two or three sums in Mechanics and I didn't half try.     &amp;c</p>
<milestone unit="page" facs="1858-03-30_2-2.jpg" edition="handwritten"/>
<p><date when="1858-03-05">Friday 5th (March, 1858).</date></p>
<p>After attending prayer this morning as I am wont to do, I returned and after breakfast I repaired to my books for a little while though not very intent for I didn't expect to be called on and was not, so I did not improve much by that recitation.  But this evening expecting to be called upon in Greek I studied it hard for a little while, though much to my <sic corr="surprise">supprize</sic> I was not and still more was I <sic corr="surprised">supprized</sic> when I learned it was our last recitation in Greek while in College.  Yes we have graduated in that department and perhaps we have recited our last lesson under old "Dixet" and will give old Pint an other trial in latin.</p>
<p>As this is Friday the evening for Senior speeches we had two this evening which turned out to be a discussion though they were written beforehand, one, Allen, that first spoke was in favor of Missionary cause while Woodson who succeeded was opposed to it so it was very interesting.</p>
<p><date when="1858-03-06">Saturday 6th (March, 1858).</date></p>
<p>Saturday being the day for debate I met at the hall this morning at the usual time and after witnessing the inniciation of two members, the roll was called for debate. Question:  "Should a woman be recognized as a citizen of the United States?"  I took the affirmative side, no I believe I took the negative but I know I did not have much to say on it and the affirmative gained the question.  After getting my dinner I received a letter from home which I was glad to receive and immediately answered it and wrote an other at the same time to Uncle Pierce Bridges.  And since night I have occupied my time reading the life of Washington and made a finish of it tonight.  So I am through with an other week's business.</p>
<p><date when="1858-03-08">Monday, March 8th (1858).</date></p>
<p>I have been to regular recitations today but have not recited, have been called but once and then got excused on account of ill healthy;  have a cold and sore throat and after eating a big bate of eggs I feel worse than I did before and I am really afraid I will not rest well tonight.  Although it has <pb facs="1858-03-03_1-2.jpg"/> been very cold for a week it has been snowing all day and has turned still colder tonight and I think it will be freezing in the morning but I am getting sorter tired of cold weather.  I am in hopes it will turn warm seen and remain.</p>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>