<div class="content">
<div>
<h3>The Oxford Experience Site</h3>
<p>The Oxford Experience Project began with the request of a faculty
  member at Oxford College who teaches a writing class, to use primary source documents in her
  writing class, and to present the documents and student papers on the web. A
  consultation team of librarians from Oxford, from the Manuscript,
  Archives, and Rare Book Library (MARBL), and the Beck Center for Electronic
  Collections at Emory, met with the faculty and decided to engage the
  students in text analysis that included text markup in XML.</p>
<p>The team hired a student to gather texts that were interesting from
  <a href="#sr">an undergraduate perspective</a>. With the assistance of the staff of
  MARBL and the Archives, she gathered and scanned images of a variety
  of letters, diary entries, class lists, and student produced
  documents of various kinds. The group tested the markup instruction
  on themselves and made necessary adjustments. </p>
<p>During the semester students selected texts to study and
  transcribe. They researched the situation that produced the
  document, and visited the archives to see the original. After some
  instruction in encoding, they added markup to their
  document. Finished documents were loaded to the development website
  for class presentation. Some of the documents at this production
  site also include papers that the students wrote for the class
  about their document.</p>
<p>The letters have titles as assigned by the students. The encoding has been normalized to Beck Center practices.</p>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Related Oxford Sites</h3>
<p>Students used the <a href="http://www.emory.edu/OXFORD/EarlyEmoryPhotos/">archive of early photos</a> to research the people who are named in their document.</p>
<p>Some of the collections came from <a href="http://marbl.library.emory.edu">MARBL</a>, and the <a href="http://marbl.library.emory.edu/FindingAids/index.html">finding aids</a> there may give more information about the people mentioned in the documents.</p>
</div>
</div>