<TEI xml:id="oe1907song3" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>1907 Class Song, Emory College, an electronic edition</title>
<author><name type="person" reg="Hind, A. T.">A. T. Hind</name></author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Erika Farr</name>
	  <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>1907 Class Song from 1907 Class Book, Emory College; Walter Turner Candler Papers, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <date>July 3 2007</date>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Siobhain Rivera, </name>
          <resp>Student Assistant.</resp>
        </respStmt>
        <item>XML tags inserted in compliance with TEI guidelines.</item>
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<front/>
<body>
<div type="song">
<head>Class Song.</head>
<byline>Words by A. T. Hind.</byline>
<stage rend="italic">Tune: In Dear Old Georgia.</stage>
<lg type="stanza">
<head>I.</head>
<l>In the days of yore, when younger lads, we thought of Emory;</l>
<l>We wondered if we'd e'er be Em'ry men;</l>
<l>We thought -- and truly -- 'twould be great to study in her halls,</l> 
<l>But vague our thoughts, our hopes, our dreamings then.</l>
<l>But now on looking backward, we see our college days,</l> 
<l>And forward are the scenes of worldy strife;</l>
<l>The time now quickly moves apace to when we'll say good bye</l>
<l>To joys and sorrows of our college life.</l>
</lg>
<lg>
<head>II.</head>
<l>Her name is fairer than the name of any flower that blooms,</l>
<l>No name, but one, gives joy so pure and true;</l>
<l>Her sweet aromas, softly breathed and scattered over life,</l>
<l>Are pure, refreshing as the morning dew;</l>
<l>In every land and country, where e'er her sons may be,</l>
<l>She speaks a noble message, clear and true;</l>
<l>We're Em'ry men, we'll sing again, as from her halls we go,</l>
<l>And proudly wear the Orange and Blue.</l>
</lg>
<lg><head>III.</head>
<l>The classes that have gone before have sung their songs of praise,</l>
<l>Have paid their fitting tribute to her worth,</l>
<l>With colors floating gaily adding merit to their songs,</l>
<l>But now they bear her flag through all the earth;</l>
<l>And we of nineteen-seven, our carol proudly sing--</l>
<l>You'll pardon us if we should seem to boast,</l>
<l>And place with pride the White and Blue above the other flags,</l>
<l>And say 'tis we who love old Em'ry most.</l>
</lg>
<lg><head>CHORUS.</head>
<l>To dear old Em'ry, our college home,</l> 
<l>Our hearts will wander, though far we roam,</l>
<l>To her no sons can more faithful be:</l>
<l>Our Alma Mater, our Emory.</l>
</lg>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>