<TEI xml:id="oeDanielPatrick.01" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
<teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
	<titleStmt>
            <title>W.A. Candler letter to his brother, <date when="1897-04-30"> April 30, 1897</date>, an electronic edition</title>
            <author>
		  <name type="person">
		    <choice>
		      <sic>Warren Akin Candler</sic>
		      <reg>Candler, Warren A. (Warren Akin), 1857-1941</reg>
		    </choice>
		  </name>
	    </author>
	</titleStmt>
	<extent></extent>
	<publicationStmt>
		<publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
		<pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
		<date>2007</date>
		<availability>
			<p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original contributions made by the Oxford 
Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the 
contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, 
provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's 
availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory 
University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  
30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  
beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
	<respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
	  <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <name>Alice Hickcox</name>
		<resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
	</respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Letter from Warren Akin Candler to his brother, April 30, 1897; Manuscript, 
Archive, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
<listPerson>
          <person xml:id="thyun">
            <persName>
              <forename>T.</forename>
              <forename>H.</forename>
              <surname>Yun</surname>
            </persName>
            <persName>
              <forename>Ch'i-ho</forename>
              <surname>Yun</surname>
            </persName>
            <birth when="1865">
              <placeName>
                <country>Korea</country>
              </placeName>
            </birth>
            <death when="1945-12-06">December 6, 1945</death>
          </person>
          <person xml:id="wac">
            <persName>
              <forename>Warren</forename>
              <forename>Akin</forename>
              <surname>Candler</surname>
            </persName>
            <birth when="1857-08-23">
              <placeName>
                <settlement type="county">Carroll County</settlement>
                <region type="state">Georgia</region>
                <country>United States</country>
              </placeName>
            </birth>
            <death when="1941-09-25">
              <placeName>
                <settlement type="city">Atlanta</settlement>
                <region type="state">Georgia</region>
                <country>United States</country>
              </placeName>
            </death>
          </person>
          <person xml:id="tsoong">
            <persName>
              <forename>Kia</forename>
              <forename>Tsing</forename>
              <surname>Tsoong</surname>
            </persName>
            <persName>
              <forename>George</forename>
              <surname>Bell</surname>
            </persName>
          </person>
	</listPerson>

	<listOrg>
	  <org>
	    <name xml:id="EC">Emory College</name>
	    <placeName>
	    <settlement>Oxford</settlement>
	    <region>Georgia</region>
	    </placeName>
	  </org>
	</listOrg>

	<listPlace>
	  <place>
	    <placeName>
	      <settlement>Oxford</settlement>
	      <region>Georgia</region>
	    </placeName>
	  </place>
	</listPlace>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, 
as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for 
educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some 
exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date> 
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>
        <name>Daniel Real</name> and 
		<name>Patrick Jamieson</name> transcribed and encoded the letter on <date when="2007-11-06">November 6, 2007</date>.
      </change>
      <change>On <date when="2008-10-03">October 3, 2008</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name>, Electronic Text Specialist, revised the encoded and corrected the transcription.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<front>
<div type="critical_introduction" xml:id="oeDanielPatrick.04">
<docAuthor>Daniel Real</docAuthor>
<head>Dr. Adriane Ivey<lb/>
English 101 Expository Writing<lb/>
<date>9 December 2007</date>.<lb/>
The Students, Religion, and Teachings of Emory<lb/>
Connecting Emory to Colleges Then and Now</head>
<p>Given the multitude of issues such as course selection, diversity, discipline, and countless others, surrounding any single university, let alone universities as a whole, making any broad and encompassing analysis seems impossible. But by looking at the larger tapestry through an understanding of the individual threads, one is able to comprehend many complicated topics. It is with this larger picture that this essay will concern itself. I wish to bring three threads of this tapestry into the weave. My topics were chosen based on the research done on a letter written by Warren Akin Candler to his brother in 1897, discussing the rioting that had occurred on campus in late April of that year. First, I will compare the behavior and daily life of a contemporary undergraduate to that of an undergraduate in a nineteenth century college, and at Emory in particular. Second, I wish to discuss the founding of Emory as a Methodist institution and the effects there in.  Finally, I will look at the idea of academic freedom, both at Emory and several other key colleges throughout America, and how Germany's ideas of <hi rend="italic">Lehrfreheit</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Lemfreiheit</hi> influenced American campuses.</p>

<p>The contemporary image of the nineteenth century student is one of dignity, elegance, and civility. However, I wish to discuss primarily the disciplinary aspect of a student's daily life. With more time I would also have liked to explore living arrangements, extra curricular activities and Core disciplinary material. A large amount of information is available in the Emory 

<pb n="Real 2"/>

yearbooks and course catalogs on just such information, however due to a lack of time I, unfortunately, am not able to cover such information in any satisfactory manner. There are numerous writings on student discipline, or lack thereof, in the 1800's. Today we imagine earlier students attending classes in suit and tie, always taking care to use proper English. Their serious faces seem to establish an air of formality and order not found in students today. However this is far from the reality of their behavior. Instead disorder and general havoc were commonplace: "Colleges of the early republic were besieged by student riots and disorder" (Hessinger 239). The college life of the late 1800's was not nearly as prim and proper as photos would have you believe.</p>

<p>When one looks at the history of colleges as a whole, there are some common threads that run up to the development of the contemporary college. Among these threads is the problem of disobedience. This problem was especially true in American colleges, which struggled to find students. The risk of seeming rule-burdened was too great for many colleges. For American colleges, an independent education and a minimum of rules was a way to differentiate themselves from their European, and particularly British, counterparts. This belief in an independent education was a result of the progressive <hi rend="italic">mentalit"&#x00E9;"</hi> surrounding the American Revolution. How could America, the land of the free, impose a limiting set of rules upon its brilliant minds of the future? The idea of a prestige-biased hierarchy seemed out of place in a new democracy. How could one gain advantage in a democracy just by being born into it? That smacked of the old monarchy America had just rebuffed. As a result, students were treated as equals to their faculty: "the in loco parentis patriarchal ideal was badly outdated," says Hessinger (239). The idea of an independent education was vital to the new republic. American leaders,

<pb n="Real 3"/>

collegiate and otherwise, believed that "through education a man would know his rights and understand the rights of others" (237). How were collegiate leaders to balance the vital need for higher education with a less then ideal prejudice against traditional rules?</p>

<p>Colleges soon found themselves with uneducated, disruptive students who caused more problems <sic>then</sic> they were worth. Faced with such disorder, colleges were forced to expel numerous students at a time, usually due to rioting, dueling or similar disorders. As a result, a system of meritocracy was eventually developed to counter the student disorder that college officials believed "was nurtured in students' propensity to form horizontal bonds of sympathy and loyalty" (240). By implementing a merit-based system, Colleges hoped to break these horizontal bonds which prevented students from being disciplined effectively. The University of Virginia had just such an instance of student solidarity when, after less than a year of operation, "sixty-five students (more then half the student body) presented a joint resolution to the faculty in which they attested their allegiance to one another, refusing to testify against each other in any prospective investigation" of the violent confrontation between fourteen students and two professors (241). This same sort of solidarity can be seen at Emory College when Candler writes, "This week we have been investigating the workers as well as authorities are able who have no subpoena power to secure their testimony."</p>

<p>Clearly there has been a fundamental shift in the mentality of the college student. We can now see the implications of implementing a merit-based system. Student politics have become much more cut throat, with a tremendous amount of importance being placed upon the grade received, and consequently with a person's status in a merit based society. The same student-body governments that refused to testify in the nineteenth

<pb n="Real 4"/>

century now sit in judgment of their fellow students.</p>

<p>Before leaving the topic of daily life at Emory I wish to discuss the state of race relations at Emory during this period. Emory College was certainly not progressive during the 1800's. W.A. Candler is known for his segregationist beliefs, doing his best to keep the college from integrating for as long as possible. We know from other letters that a boy was expelled for being found in a room alone with a black woman, presumably engaging in sexual activity. The boy was expelled not so much for sleeping with a woman, but because the woman was black. It is ironic though, that despite this reaction, Emory was relatively progressive in Asian relations; inviting <sic>Koran</sic> and Chinese exchange students to the campus. Today Emory has a healthy diversity of ethnicities within both its faculty and student body, an improvement for which I am sure we can all be grateful.</p>

<p>There were several ways in which Emory University, then Emory College, resembled the typical nineteenth century university; but there are also many ways in which it differed. For example, the contents of William A. Candler's letter <sic>makes</sic> it clear that disorder and disobedience among the students was a problem; however, Candler's letter also suggests a religious dilemma that was unique to the Methodist universities established before the civil war. Emory College was only the sixth such institution established by the Methodist church (104 Tewksbury), "opened on the <hi rend="italic">promise</hi> of interest not yet earned on subscriptions not yet collected" (57 Westmeyer). Emory's founding as a Methodist institution would have a profound effect on everything from the rules governing the campus, to the activities governing daily life, and especially impacted what types of people were attracted to the campus.</p>

<pb n="Real 5"/>

<p>The Methodist church was late to set up collegiate institutions because the church's evangelical roots did not support the principles of higher education, even for their minister. The Methodist Church was prejudiced against higher education as a whole: "In the Book of Discipline of 1784, it was stated that 'gaining knowledge is a good thing, but saving souls is better'" (Tewksbury 103). However, after the first Great Awakening in the mid 1700's, and especially the second Great Awakening in the early 1800's, the Methodist church found itself with a majority of uneducated members and lay preachers. It was not until the 1830's that a push for a more educated ministry led Methodist leaders to endorse the foundation of colleges with the expressed purpose to educate the Methodist clergy (103). By looking at the course catalogues of early Emory College, we can see how the college catered to the Methodist minister, offering discounts and tailor made courses. In the span of three decades, the Methodist church was able to construct thirty-four universities distributed widely across the United States. Emory College would be the sixth such institution founded on December 10, 1836, quickly followed by Weslyan College in Macon, Georgia just thirteen days later. Lagrange Female College, founded on January 15, 1847, was the last Methodist university established in Georgia during the time before the Civil War (104).</p>


<p>Much of the American higher education system can be traced back to Germany where the ideas of <hi rend="italic">Lehrfreiheit</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Lernfreiheit</hi> were originated (xii Westrneyer). Paul Westmeyer defines these two terms in his book <hi rend="italic">An Analytical History of American Higher Education</hi> writing:

<quote>The essential freedom to discover new information, to do research, known as <hi rend="italic">Lehrfreiheit</hi>, is one of these influences that is still profoundly visible here.. . . Actually, the <hi rend="italic">Lehrfreiheit</hi> was the idea that new knowledge was valuable whether or not it made a

<pb n="Real 6"/>

contribution to everyday life; the counter part for students was <hi rend="italic">Lernfreiheit</hi>, the freedom to learn what one desired. (Xii)</quote></p>

<p>The impact the German system had on the first American colleges cannot be understated, "between 1818 and 1914, over 10,000 American scholars had attended German universities" (102). Again, Emory was late in picking up the trend. In 1897 courses were still laid out for students. Rather <sic>then</sic> allowing them the ability to choose which courses to take, a student would choose which discipline of study they wished to pursue and then take the predetermined courses. I believe this old structure was retained because of the strong connections to the Methodist church. Emory was originally established to educate ministers for the church; there was no need for doctoral programs, and there was little desire to expand the frontiers of knowledge. It would not be until Emory College became Emory University that it would begin the process of educating students for the sake of education.</p>

<p>This paper is a result of studying a letter written by Warren Akin Candler to his brother. I wish to briefly discuss the decisions in editing that letter. My partner and I chose to make as few changes to the letter as possible. It was difficult because we included items like letterhead in the transcription. This makes formatting a real challenge. We also wished to preserve the small edit that Candler made to his letter, however we are still unsure how to tag this difference. Fortunately, an image of each page of the letter will eventually accompany the document.</p>

<p>Emory has grown from a small Methodist college outside of Atlanta into one of the top ranked colleges in the nation. Its history is part of a larger movement towards higher education in America. Discipline remains a problem, though surprisingly things may have improved on this particular front, considering that there are few riots on campus. Emory's ties to the Methodist church have, for the most part, been severed although there are still some who wish to restore

<pb n="Real 7"/>

this bond. Emory has certainly made great progress in becoming a full university focused on expanding the frontiers of knowledge. And at its core still stand the student body, changed in appearance and behavior, but still the focus of an effort to educate.</p>

<pb n="Real 8"/>

<div type="bibliography">
<head>Works Cited</head>
<bibl>Hessinger, Rodney. <title level="a">"The Most Powerful Instrument of College Discipline': Student Disorder and the Growth of Meritocracy in the Colleges of the Early Republic."</title> <title level="j">History of Education Quarterly </title>39.3 (1999): 237-262. America: History &#x0026; Life. EBSCO. Hoke O'Kelley Memorial Library, Oxford, GA.</bibl>

<bibl>Tewksbury, Donald G. <title level="m">The Founding of American Colleges and Universities Before the Civil.</title> <pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>: <publisher>Teachers College, Columbia University, 1932.</publisher></bibl>

<bibl>Westmeyer, Paul. <title level="m">An Analytical History of American Higher Education.</title> 2nd. <pubPlace>Springfield, Il</pubPlace>: <publisher>Charles C Thomas: Publisher, LTD., 1997.</publisher></bibl>
</div>
</div>
<div type="critical_introduction" xml:id="oeDanielPatrick.02">
<docAuthor>Patrick Jamieson</docAuthor>
<head>English 101 - Dr. Ivey<lb/>
<date>December 10, 2007</date><lb/>
Early Roots in Modern Education</head>
<p>In a small town forty miles east of what would eventually become Atlanta, Emory
College laid down its roots as an institution based on the ideals of Methodist education.
The college would expand over the next few decades, eventually moving to suburban
Atlanta and become a university with rich foundations in research and scholarship.
Despite this move, the true history and character of Emory remain at Oxford. In this
small town, it was Rev. Warren Candler who led Emory during the turn of the century as
its distinguished President. Candler was an honors graduate of Emory College in 1875,
and despite his young age, he was licensed to be a preacher and was later admitted to the
North Georgia Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South ("Candler
Biography"). Candler led Emory through times of great hardship and tremendous
change. The "Oxford Experience" project is intended to highlight and analyze important
pieces of Emory's history (mostly handwritten letters and journals) in order to better
understand what life was like in earlier times. The "Oxford Experience" focuses on
leaders, visionaries and exceptional students of Emory from the late nineteenth century to
the early twentieth century. My part of this project focuses on a letter written by Rev.
Candler to his brother, who can be reasonably assumed to be Asa G. Candler, the founder
of the Coca-Cola Company and an Emory Philanthropist. The letter details a weekend of
mayhem on the campus in which Candler discusses his feelings towards those involved
as well as what happened. However, the letter does more than simply recap a bad
weekend on the campus to Candler's brother it exemplifies the spirit and history of
<pb n="Jamieson 2"/>
American education around the turn of the century. Emory's rich history as well as
Warren Candler's immense contributions to the school are all evident from this letter. In
addition, learning about a specific student mentioned in Candler's letter better highlights -
student life at Emory during the time.</p>
<p>Warren Candler was a unique man who served Emory very well during his tenure
as President. Candler entered Emory College in 1875, and soon after, became a
"dynamic and highly successful revival preacher." ("Candler Biography"). Candler
practiced a "strenuous, emotional evangelism" which in turn produced "mass
conversions" ("Candler Biography"). He was a leader of '"New Puritanism,'" a
movement that was prominent in the South in the 1880's which emphasized old-doctrines
and the bible's inspiration ("Candler Biography"). Candler was soon elected President of
Emory College where he brought his strict Methodist philosophy with him. According to
historian Henry Morton Bullock in his book <hi rend="italic">A History of Emory University</hi>, "[t]rue to his
life before and since, [Candler's] presidency was characterized by a series of definite
changes arrived at with directness and speed. There is practically no record of his
underlying educational philosophy. It must be assumed that his educational theories were
in the main those of the orthodox classical and religious mold of his day" (Bullock 220).
Candler was a man deeply committed to his faith--he wrote numerous books and articles
in support of the Methodist Church and religious based education. Candler argues in his
1904 book <hi rend="italic">Great Revivals and the Great Republic</hi> that a new "Great Awakening" will
occur in America, one that will be "a revival of religion--not a political reform nor a
philanthropic scheme of social amelioration" ("Great Revivals and the Great Republic"
313). Candler also had many thoughts about the South and its place with education. His
<pb n="Jamieson 3"/>
thoughts show the poor state of educational facilities in the South but, at the same time,
forecast the greatness that Emory would have later in the health-sciences field. "Why
should not men and women in Atlanta and Georgia and the South unite to make in this
city an institution for research that will further learning and extend opportunities to the
poor <sic>bring</sic> young men of our section?" Candler writes in his essay "A Case Which Both
Honors and Humiliates the South" ("Emory Bulletin" 11). He continues to write that the
South "produces great minds, but they must leave [the South] to find the advantages
which they should have" ("Emory Bulletin" 11). Later in his life Candler would be
incredibly active in foreign ministry and make over twenty trips to Cuba, where he
attempted to form a native ministry. In addition, Candler visited the Orient and Korea on
several missions ("Candler Biography").</p>
<p>The first thing I noted when beginning to research the actual image of the letter
and transcribe it into a text document was the complexity of Candler's handwriting which
made it often very difficult to read. I suspect that this could indicate a certain urgency of
the letter Candler was writing to his brother Asa ("Candler Letter" 1). The two brothers
wrote many letters to each other and their correspondence is extensive. Many examples
of their correspondence are available in the Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
(MARBL) at the Robert W. Woodruff Library of Emory University, Since the two
brothers were so close, they could talk candidly about issues such as the one Warren is
writing about. After I saw the original letter at MARBL and not the scanned version, his
writing became much clearer. Most of the words I had trouble reading that did not
appear legible could be reasonably inferred from the context of the sentence. Candler
initially begins describing the mayhem that occurred on campus. "Bonfires were kindled
<pb n="Jamieson 4"/>
on the campus, bombs belonging to the contractor of the new building were burned,
pistols were fired," Candler writes ("Candler Letter" 1). The most perplexing and
unexplained element of Candler's letter comes on the third page when Candler refers to a
student, "Albert", who was involved in the incident despite his belief("Candler Letter" 3).
This person was the subject of much of my research and led me to many different sources.
The way that Candler mentions Albert immediately made me think that he was a very
well-thought-of student and someone who would not be characteristically involved in
such mayhem. In addition, I always had views of students from this time period being
very prim and proper. It is hard to imagine so many students being involved in such
actions. Emory College was a small, regional, Methodist school during this time period;
the thought of a student not being incredibly straight laced makes for very interesting
research.</p>
<p>I began this research the most logical way possible; utilizing Emory's yearbooks 
from this time period. The <hi rend="italic">Zodiac</hi> would have been an excellent first step if they
completely spelled out a student's first name instead of abbreviating their first and middle
names. The only students who received their full name in the yearbook were the seniors,
This dilemma made finding "Albert" far more difficult. In addition, the supplemental
materials I looked at, including the Alumni Directory as well as the Catalogue, provided
me with the same problem. Beginning with the 1897 seniors I found one student named
Albert Dozier Kean, a well-esteemed member of the class of 1897 ("The Zodiac," 1897).
He was active in many clubs and organizations and all-in-all appeared to be a good
student. This is part of the reason why I found Albert Kean to be very fitting of the
student Candler describes in his letter. Candler does expresses a sense of fondness
<pb n="Jamieson 5"/>
towards this student, noting that he "had not supposed Albert had participated in it but
today he confessed to me what he had to do with the disorder on the campus" ("Candler
Letter" 3-4). I was not satisfied with Albert Kean fitting the profile of the "Albert"
described in Candler's letter however, because there was no additional information about
him that would lead me to believe he was involved. My biggest question at this time was
whether or not there would be disciplinary records, since the letter mentions that Albert
would be suspended for two weeks.</p>
<p>Upon further research, through the Special Collections in MARBL as well as the
1898 <hi rend="italic">Zodiac</hi>, I was able to find another Albert who better exemplified the profile. Albert
Danner Thomson was an 1898 graduate of Emory College, a member of the Sigma Alpha
Epsilon fraternity, a forward on the Basketball team, participant in the pentathlon contest
and a center-fielder for the baseball team ("The Zodiac" 1898). Thomson was very close
to Warren Candler; he accompanied Candler on his travels to Japan and Korea and <sic>jpet</sic>
close correspondence with him. Many examples of this correspondence can be found in
the Special Collections in MARBL. In addition, Thomson's later life was filled with
success; he was a powerful Atlanta businessman, served on the City-Council of Atlanta
and as Executive Secretary to Mayor Asa Griggs Candler. ("Albert Danner Thomson 
Papers"). Thomson's close connection with the Candler family is very evident and these
connections led me to believe that Albert Thomson is the person mentioned by Candler. I
visited the Special Collections at MARBL and found the exact proof that I needed that
Albert Thomson was the student described in the letter. Through the "Albert Danner
Thomson Papers," a five box collection of various letters, newspaper clippings,
photographs, travel documents and even report cards, I was able to begin searching for
<pb n="Jamieson 6"/>
letters or disciplinary records that would prove Thomson to be part of this conspiracy. I
found a letter from William S. Thomson, Albert Thomson's father, dated May 3, 1897.
William Thomson was a successful lawyer from Atlanta. The letter begins saying, "Dr.
Candler wrote to me Saturday, but I was very busy and did not have a chance to read his
letter until after I got home. It disrupted me greatly although he wrote about you very
kindly, and commended your truthfulness....I have written Dr. C by this mail, asking him
to be as lenient as he can. I want to do what is best, but I cannot think what is best"
(Thomson 1). This provides exact proof that Thomson's son Albert was directly involved
in the mayhem on campus. However, Albert's father does not appear to be angry at all--
he appears more disappointed. He continues by saying, "I accept your statements and
commend you for telling the truth. You are right in your thinking that I looked after
you....If you have to leave Oxford, I think its better that you should come home, but if
you would feel better to go over to Covington, you have my [blessing]" (Thomson 2).
This letter was the definite proof I needed to know the identity of Albert as well as to
give me some insight into his life and character. Through my additional research through
his papers, journals, photographs and other materials I was able to see what a successful
life he lived. He had traveled to the Far East with Warren Candler on several trips and
wrote extensive travel diaries describing his exotic journeys. Knowing who the 
mysterious "Albert" was from Candler's letter helps better explain college life. This tiny
piece of information better explains what a college student was like from this time period,
what types of disciplinary action were taken towards students like this and why crimes
like this occurred. Despite the sometimes difficult handwriting, Candler's letter was able
<pb n="Jamieson 7"/>
to come together has a complete statement on what occurred at the Emory campus more
than a century ago.</p>
<p>Through Candler's letter, the overall history and character of Emory are well
explained. In addition, the overall philosophies of American education in the nineteenth
century are noted. Emory's transition from a small Methodist college in rural Georgia to
a major research institution did not come without hard work. "The development of
Emory University," Historian Henry Bullock writes, "reflects many of the major trends in
higher education in the South <sic>ruing</sic> the last hundred years.. ..Since the Civil War the
institution has typified and not infrequently has led the struggle of the South to provide
for itself indigenous college and University education. Throughout, Emory has
maintained and adjusted its work in the light of a constant purpose to build Christian
character" (Bullock 7). Education in America was also growing at an exponential rate;
In 1880 4,450 Bachelor's degrees were awarded and just a decade later in 1890 6,324
Bachelor's degrees were awarded according to Robert Geiger's essay "The Crisis of Old
Order: The Colleges in the 1890s" (Geiger 273). "The anomalous situation began to change," Geiger writes, "in the 1890s as the number of college graduates more than
doubled....This vision of the place and purpose of college could be embraced by
university presidents, alumni supporters, and collegians themselves. In the opening
decades of the new century, it became the predominant image of American higher
education" (Geiger 275). Across the country, colleges and universities were growing at a
fast pace and more and more people were beginning to attend them. In addition, Emory
was evolving to the changing standards of higher education at the time. In 1892,
significant changes were made to the curriculum under Candler's presidency. According
<pb n="Jamieson 8"/>
to Bullock's book, "In that year the old bachelor of science and English literature was
dropped, and full four year courses of study leading to bachelor of science and bachelor
of philosophy degrees were introduced" (Bullock 221). It is incredibly interesting that
Candler saw no place for industrial or business courses in the college. Courses in
bookkeeping and telegraphy were not present at Emory until 1889 (Bullock 222).
Around this same time, the Emory Law School was being formed and graduates were
given a bachelor of laws degree (Bullock 222). In addition, Candler was very interested
in having a school which could train preachers. Candler had an incredible outlook on
Emory and remained positive. "A College sustained by such a constituency," he writes in
<hi rend="italic">The Emory Phoenix</hi>, "can never die. Emory College is made deathless because
encompassed by arms of love, for there is nothing so enduring as love" ("Emory
Phoenix" 103). It can be assumed that students and professors had a difficult time in
college during these early days of Emory. Students now can say that forty miles from
Atlanta is not far at all, but in 1897 forty miles was an incredible distance. Warren
Candler's presence in Atlanta on this weekend signifies that he was there for a very
important event. In the era before Henry Ford's "Model-T" and other mass-produced
automobiles, transportation for this long of a distance was very difficult. The classes also
appeared to be very rigorous. A look at Albert Thomson's report card shows his course
schedule in 1897 to contain sixteen different courses he had to attend including moral
philosophy (taught by Dr. Candler), Calculus, English Literature and Declamation.
Thomson had six absences from moral philosophy and twenty-two from chapel, showing
he was far from perfect ("Report of the Standing"). At the beginning of my research for
this project I had assumed college students were far different in 1897 then they are now.
<pb n="Jamieson 9"/>
However, now that I have seen the life of several students, and learned about the
character and history of education during this time period I am able to see many
similarities.</p>
<p>Emory has certainly evolved from a small, regional, Methodist school to a
nationally known research institution which consistently ranks among the best in the
country every year. Despite the major changes that Emory has gone through over the
past century, including a move to Atlanta, extreme growth in faculty and students,
development of graduate and professional programs and a move from religious affiliation,
the character that was present in 1897 is still present today. Warren Candler was a man
who helped bring Emory into new times. As education was changing at the turn of the
century, Candler was able to foresee these changes and help Emory move into the
forefront of education. He had great goals for Emory to become renown in many
different aspects and help bring it to the level it is at today. His letter serves as a vital
primary source to learn about what life was like during this time period. One of the most
important parts of his letter is his willingness to forgive Albert for what he did on the
campus. Researching Albert led me to many different avenues and gave me a deeper
I understanding of college life during this time period. Albert iyÃ a prime example of a
college student at Emory around the turn of the century. While every student did not start
fires or set off bombs, many got in trouble on occasion and many were heavily involved
in school activities. Albert Thomson went on to be an incredibly successful businessman
in Atlanta, and his success was in part to Warren Candler's guidance while Thomson
attended Emory. His close connections with the Candler family are evident throughout
his papers and collections at MARBL. The primary purpose of the "Oxford Experience"
<pb n="Jamieson 10"/>
project is not simply to type a letter so it can be searched on the internet, rather it is a
learning experience; a project designed to give students the opportunity to research and
understand life during this time period. Utilizing Candler's letter as well as many other
sources, I feel that I have been able to better understand college life, the history and
character of Emory, as well as an overall history of American Education during this time
period.</p>
<pb n="Jamieson 11"/>
<div type="bibliography">
<head>Works Cited</head>
<bibl><title level="u">Albert Danner Thomson Papers.</title> Atlanta: Special Collections, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare
Book Library, Robert W. Woodruff Library, Emory University.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Bullock, Henry M.</author> <title level="m">History of Emory University</title>. <pubPlace>Nashville</pubPlace>: <publisher>Parthenon P</publisher>, <date>1936</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Candler, Warren A.</author> <title level="a">"A Case Which Both Honors and Humiliates the South."</title> <title level="j">Bulletin of Emory
University</title>. <pubPlace>Atlanta</pubPlace>: <publisher>Emory University</publisher>, <date>1918</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Candler, Warren A.</author> <editor>Ed. Herbert S. Phillips</editor>. <title level="m">The Emory Phoenix</title> <date>May 1897</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Candler, Warren A.</author> <title level="m">Great Revivals and the Great Republic.</title> <pubPlace>Nashville</pubPlace>: <publisher>House of the M.E.
Church, South, Lamar &#x0026; Barton, Agents,</publisher> <date>1924</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Candler, Warren A.</author> <title level="u">Letter to Brother.</title> <date>30 Apr. 1897.</date> Special Collections, Manuscript, Archives,
and Rare Book Library, Robert W. Woodruff Library, Emory University, Atlanta.</bibl>
<bibl><author>Geiger, Robert.</author> <title level="a">"The Crisis of the Old Order."</title> <title level="m">The American College in the Nineteenth Century.</title>
<pubPlace>Nashville</pubPlace>: <publisher>Vanderbilt UP</publisher>, <date>2000</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><title level="u">Report of the Standing January to June, 1897.</title> Emory College. Special Collections, Manuscript,
Archives, and Rare Book Library, Robert W. Woodruff Library, Emory University, <date>1897</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><editor>Students Of Emory College, comp.</editor> <title level="s">The Zodiac.</title> <pubPlace>Atlanta</pubPlace>: <publisher>Franklin Printing &#x0026; Company</publisher>, <date>1898</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><editor>Students Of Emory College, comp.</editor> <title level="s">The Zodiac.</title> <pubPlace>Atlanta</pubPlace>: <publisher>Franklin Printing &#x0026; Company</publisher>, <date>1897</date>.</bibl>
<bibl><title level="u">Thomson, William S. Letter to Albert Thomson.</title> <date>3 May 1897</date>. Albert Danner Thomson Papers.
Special Collections, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Robert W. Woodruff
Library, Emory University, Atlanta.</bibl>
<bibl><title level="a">"Warren Akin Candler."</title><title level="m">Dictionary of American Biography.</title> Biography Resource Center. Robert
W. Woodruff Library, Emory University, Atlanta. 13 Nov. 2007.</bibl>
</div>
</div>
</front>
<body>
<div type="letter" xml:id="oeDanielPatrick.03">
<pb facs="1897-04-30_1.jpg"/>
<head>[Letter from Warren Akin Candler to his brother, April 30, 1897]</head>
<opener>
<address><addrLine>Emory College, President's Office </addrLine></address>
<dateline>
<name type="place">Oxford, Ga.,</name>
<date when="1897-04-30">April, 30 1897</date>
</dateline>
<salute>My dear Brother:</salute></opener><p>I 
am pained thus to
send you this letter</p>

	<p>On last Thursday <date when="1897-04">April</date> and Friday
  nights whilst I was in Atlanta there
was serious disorder here. Bonfires
were kindled on the campus, bombs
belonging to the contractor on the new 
building were burned; pistols were
fired; <name type="person"><choice><reg>Dr. Moore</reg><sic>Dr. Moore's</sic></choice></name>  fencing was

<pb facs="1897-04-30_2.jpg"/>


damaged, and <name type="person">Dr. Haygood's</name> professional
sign was pulled down &#x0026; carried
to <name type="person"><choice><reg>Jarrell, Charles Crawford, 1874-1961.</reg><sic>Prof. Jarrell's</sic></choice></name> </p>

<p>  One of the causes 
which prevented my recessing in
Atlanta over Sunday as I greatly
desired <add place="supralinear">to do</add> was a telephone message
advising my return here on the 
account of this disorder.</p>

	        <p>This week we have been 

<pb facs="1897-04-30_3.jpg"/>

investigating the matter as well as 
authorities are able who have no
subpoena  power to secure  their testimony</p>

	<p>I had not supposed <name type="person"><choice><reg>Thomson, Albert Danner, 1877-1953.</reg><sic>Albert</sic></choice></name>
had participated in it but today <date when="1897-04-30">April 30.</date>
he confessed to me what he had
to do with the disorder on the campus.
He denied having had any part in
<pb facs="1897-04-30_4.jpg"/>


 other parts of the disorder. He has been suspended for two weeks 
and demerited.</p>

	<p>Others who added to the offense
of disorder, falsehood before the 
faculty when questioned, have been 
dismissed.</p>

	<p>I write the facts to you with a
heary heart.  If while I am away 

<pb facs="1897-04-30_5.jpg"/>


pleading for Christian education 
buys whom I implicitly trusted
can bring dishonor to the institution I 
feel like laying down the work 
as a vain and impossible task.  
Yet I am conscious of leaving the book.  
I know how to make Christian men 
and I must learn my familiar in God's hands.</p>

<closer>With deep regrets.
<salute>  I am Yours Truly, </salute>
<signed><name type="person" ref="#wac">W.A. 
Candler</name></signed>
</closer>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
