<TEI xml:id="oecarmichael.01" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Diary Entry of Marion Walter Carmichael, <date when="1898-02-26">February 26, 1898</date>, an electronic edition</title>
<author><name type="person"><reg>Carmichael, Marion Walter, 1870-1935.</reg><sic>Marion Walter Carmichael</sic></name></author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Diary Entry of Marion Walter Carmichael, Marion Walter Carmichael Papers, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change><date>10-27-08</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected transctiption.</change>
      <change><date>10-15-08</date> <name>Stewart Varner</name> migrated the coding to p5.
      </change>
      <change>
        <date>10/18/07</date>
          <name>David Joseph</name> and <name>Imran Merchant </name>
        transcribed the document and added XML tags in compliance with TEI guidelines.
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div>
<pb facs="1898-Journal_Entry_1.jpg"/>
<head>[Diary entry of Marion Walter Carmichael]</head>
<p>
	In some near or remote future, should my eye change to fall upon this page, I shall recall in all distinctness this day - Feb 26th, 1898.</p>
<p>
	How miserable are the effects of negligence of duty! For more than three weeks I have delayed writing my spring term speech, and not until last night did I try hard to accomplish this task. But lo! I accomplished nothing! I read a part of Emerson's Essay on Self-reliance, think-<pb facs="1898-Journal_Entry_2.jpg"/>ing that it might quicken mental action. But after trying to write until half past one o'clock, I could do nothing that was satisfactory to my own mind. I went to bed, slept until nearly seven o'clock, and arose with the determination of making another trial this morning. So after breakfast I gathered up Lee's History of the U.S., Sargents Standard Speaker, and writing tablet and set out for the woods. The morning is bright and nature seems to lend every aid. I am now in a little patch of pine woods of five or ten years growth by an old gully about ten feet deep which in all probability is the result of thoughtless <sic>antibellum</sic> farming, about one mile north west of Andrew Hall. What success I may have today I cannot now predict. But this much I know, that there is no probability of my enjoying the <pb facs="1898-Journal_Entry_3.jpg"/>Arbor Day exercises of the class of '98, of which I am a member, unless I make one more earnest effort to write my contemplated eulogy on Thomas Jefferson. May my mind be quickened by Him who has all power.</p>


<p><date>
March 3rd, 1898</date></p>
	<p>This has been another trying day in my life. I arose this morning being awakened by the cook's call for the keys to kitchen, and learned that my butler was still sick and that the boy in his place had not returned. Consequently I had to look after the <sic>dinning</sic> room and did get to study my mental philosophy lesson on I should. And was called upon, failed, and was rebuked. But alas! The sun does not shine bright every day. </p> 


</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
