<TEI xml:id="Letter_from_Munson_to_Sister.xml" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter from Munson to Brother, <date when="1848-10-22">Oct. 22, 1848</date>, an electronic edition</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Munson, G. B.</reg>
	      <sic>G.B. Munson</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2009</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2009, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
         <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <name>Jeff Galle</name>
	  <name>Mark Swails</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Munson Letter to Brother, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>Oct.05,2009</date>   
          <name>Timmins, Meghann</name>,<name>Anderson, Wesley</name> and <name> Boykin, William</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
  <body>
	<div type= "letter">
	<pb facs="brother_origp1.jpg"/>
	<head>Letter from Munson to Brother</head>
	

<dateline><name type="place">Emory College</name><date when="1848-10-22">Oct 22th</date></dateline>

<salute>Dear Brother</salute>

<p>I received <choice> <sic>youre</sic><reg> you're </reg> </choice> kind favours a few days ago and I now hasten a reply. I was glad to hear that all was well and in good spirits. I have no news to give you at <choice> <sic>pressent</sic> <reg> present </reg> </choice> but in reply to youre letter I think that it would <sic>bea</sic> doing 
injustice to you and also myself not to say something to you about how I am getting <sic>allong</sic> in college persuits I have concluded with the advice of you and all other friends and relations that a regular course of studies would <sic>bea</sic> better now and in future for me and I have <sic>there fore</sic> conclude that what time I have to spend in obtaining this most precious gift which can <sic>bea</sic> bestowed mankind in general that I will myself try and get as complete a knowledge of all the languages as the time I have to spend <sic>uppon</sic> this all important subject will admit.  I have <sic>there fore</sic> began a regular course and if there is any possicle chance of reaping any honours I will try and do my part. I hope that you will not think that I am flattering myself of ever becomming a great man ye I intind to improve my time as much as I possibly can.</p>

<p>I wish that you could no some of our professors especially <sic>Dr Longstreat</sic> you would think that did not have enough  sense to find his way from the <sic>chappel</sic>

<pb facs="brother_origp2.jpg"/>

 back home again but when you come to <sic>converce</sic> with him you will find him to be about as smart a man as ever <sic>youre</sic> <sic>Dr Finley</sic> of <sic>anny</sic> others man who moves in so small a circle</p>

<p>But if you should chance to get in company with Dr. Means you would not find in his manners an appearance a more genteel man in the south or I <sic>dout</sic> whether you <sic>woul</sic> find <sic>wone</sic> better informed <sic>uppon</sic> <sic>anny</sic> subject.</p>

<p>you must write first <sic>oppertunity</sic> and give me a full account of all <sic>youre</sic> occupations and tell me how you all are a getting <sic>allong</sic> with the sugar crop. tell George Milasis and little Mary Jane that they <sic>mus</sic> write to <sic>m</sic> as they <sic>donte</sic> know how much pleasure it affords me to get <sic>anny</sic> thing from home now I <sic>donte</sic> <sic>wante</sic> you to answer this short letter but you <sic>mus</sic> tell sister <gap reason="illegible" unit="word"/> to do it you stated in <sic>youre</sic> letter that she <sic>though</sic> that I had slighted her but if so it was  not intentionally and I hope that she will look over this and I will try and make up for it <sic>uppon</sic> the other <sic>sid</sic>.</p>

<closer>
<signed><del rend="strikethrough"> your</del> <sic>youre</sic> Brother</signed>
<name>G B Munson</name></closer></div></body></text></TEI>

