<TEI xml:id="oePeed.001" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Archives by Professor M.T. Peed, <date when="1926">1926</date>, an electronic edition</title>

	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Peed, Mansfield Theodore, 1857-1925.</reg>
	      <sic>M.T. Peed</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Archives by Professor M.T. Peed,  Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1900-1999</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
             <item>Education--United States--History--20th century.</item>
             <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
             <item>Emory College--Faculty.</item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>2008-10-29</date> 
          <name>Anna Nelson-Daniel</name> and <name>Gabriel Martin</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
            <change>On <date when="2009-05-07">May 7, 2009</date> <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding, and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div>
<pb facs="peed_1.jpg"/>
<head>[Archives by Professor M.T. Peed, 1926]</head>
<p>In the fall of <date when="1891">1891</date> came the first important conflict between the classicists and the scientists of Emory College. Witherto the honors at graduation had been open exclusively to the A.B. men <del rend="strikethrough">exclusively</del>, and, to this restriction, there had been no objection, since the B.S. degree had been admitted to be an inferior one <del rend="strikethrough">degree</del>. Now, however, when four years in college were hereafter to be required alike for all three degrees, the question arose: Shall the speakerships and honors be open <unclear>ailee</unclear> to candidates for all degrees? Now, it was readily conceded that the speakerships should thus be open, but not the honors. For did [not] the honors carry the institutions stamps of scholarship [,] and was not the scholarship of the B.A. axiomatically superior to that of either of the other courses? Thus reasoned the defenders of the old learning, and they voted as they reasoned. </p>
<p>But action was not taken on the issue without earnest and prolonged debate. The Professor of Greek was opposed to any change whatsoever. The Professor of Latin was, however, willing to admit the B.Ph. men to the honors, since they took work in his department. The Professor of English by far the most cultured man in the faculty, stood firmly by the old order. The President, ever as ardent advocate of the classics, cast in his lot with these three. The four other professors arrayed them- on the side of what seemed to them a more liberal policy. Now, if there had been consuptation beforehad, a motion would have been made that honors should be made to all without references to degree lines. What was offered was intended as a compromise.  But it met as decided opposition as would have been <unclear>encowothonors shoexdrenetprpposalL</unclear>. It was moved that, in any case, two honors should go to A.B. seniors, one each to the men in the others, they should be found among the first four men in scholarship in their class; but, if no B.Ph. or B.S. man should be found among the first four, the corresponding honor should go the next B.A. man. ON this motion, there was a tie vote, and the <unclear>ques- theomotisncthatedatedaso</unclear>the trustees for decision, and they passed the motion that was offered in the faculty. </p>
<p><del rend="strikethrough">A rather amusing thing occurred at the faculty meeting. When one of the adjunct professors attempted to vote, the President <sic>decpared</sic> him ineligible to vote. There upon he challenged the President's vote; but his challenge, of course was not sustained. </del></p>
<p>Looking, back, through the years, we see that neither side was altogether free from error, and that both sides failed to recognize the true situation<add>;</add> the question at issue was not whether the classics or <add>the</add> sciences afford the better training. Indeed, as matters then stood, the student of the classics had decidedly the advantage. For, at that time, probably not more than two or three high schools in Georgia were properly equipped with laboratory facilities; nor were the teachers themselves well-trained for scientific teaching. In the case of the modern languages, the situation was quite as bad. In <add>addition</add> the entrance requirements were unequal. For entrance to the B.Ph., nothing took place of the place of the <pb facs="peed_2.jpg"/>Greek required for the A.B.; while, for the B.S., there were no substitutes for either Greek or Latin. Of course, with their superior training, the men of the classical course were better prepared. But, in college, the effort was made to require equal <sic>wok</sic> work of all candidates for degrees. So, <sic>ont</sic> the whole, probably the regulations adopted were the best the conditions prevailing. Up to the time of their repeal, however, the honors <sic>werea awarde</sic> exactly as they would have been awarded, if open equally to all seniors.</p>
	<p>One morning in <date when="1891-11">November, 1891</date>, the community awoke to find the building between Seney Hall and the old technological building destroyed by fire. This building had been so closely shut up that it was almost entirely consumed before the fire was discovered. Fortunately it was a still night, and no damage was done to any other building. But it was seen to what danger the library on the third floor of Seney was exposed, and an agitation was begun at once for a library building arose.</p>
	<p>The students did not flock to the new degrees, although they were established in response to what was supposed to be a popular demand. Almost the whole faculty discounted the new courses, and their attitude was reinforced by the bad reputation of the old  B.S. together with the reverence with which the A.B. in which <sic>the was</sic> still regarded.</p>
	<p>The class of '92 was torn by a question of discipline which a serious mistake was made, a mistake that became very evident immediately after commencement. The class as a <sic>sems</sic>, in consequence, never to have been loyal to the college as other classes; yet from it came men that have done excellent service to the institution and the world. Among them are such as Dr. Sharp of Emory University Academy and Dr. Parks of the Georgia Normal and Industrial College, Mr. E. A. Pound, lecturer, and Prof. L.P. <sic>SMImith</sic> of Wesleyan College.</p> 
	<p>In '92 or '93, a reform was introduced in the entrance examinations. A regular schedule was drawn up and thereby one day was saved in preliminary work.</p>
	<p>In '94, Dr. Scomp retired from the faculty, and Rev. L. W. H. Harris was elected to <sic>spcceed</sic> him.</p>
	<p>The College moved on quietly for several consolidating and systematizing what it had gained. At this time, the <unclear>coun-</unclear> was suffering from the effects of the panic of '93. Emory <sic>c</sic> College was enjoying the greatest prosperity of its history. but such is man's nature that it is doubtful whether we recognize our good fortune.</p>
	<p>In the midst of the financial depression, Mr, Patillo, who had paid a part of his subscription to endowment, wished to make the remainder secure against any contingency. Accordingly he offered in payment certain lands in Texas. <sic>A</sic> After thorough investigation, his proposition was accepted. For several years, taxes were paid on these lands without income in about $6900.00. In ten years, these lands which had been accepted at 22000.00, were sold for $60000, thus doubling the...</p> 
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
