<TEI xml:id="oeReeves863-1907Summer" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Emory College, Summer School, Session of 1907, June 18th-August 14th, 1907, <date when="">1907</date>, an electronic edition</title>
<author><name type="person">
<choice>
      <reg>Turner, Edward K.</reg>
      <sic>Edward K. Turner</sic>
</choice>
</name>
</author>
</titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2007</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2007, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p></availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
          <name>Christine Loflin</name>
          <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Emory College, Summer School, Session of 1907, June 18th-August 14th, 1907, <!-- the collection name -->, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at 
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item>Education--United States--History--20th century.</item>
            <item>Education--Georgia.</item>
            <item>College students--Georgia.</item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>2009-10-27</date>   
          <name><!-- your name --></name> and <name><!-- a second name --></name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.</change>
<change>On May 7, 2009 <name>Alice Hickcox</name> corrected the text and encoding and added subject headings.</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<pb facs="1907-summer_1.jpg"/>
<div>
<head>Emory College<lb/> Summer School<lb/> Session of 1907<lb/> June 18th-August 14th, 1907</head>
<pb facs="1907-summer_2.jpg"/>
<div><head>AIMS</head>
<p>Many students, expecting to enter college in the fall, who find themselves deficient in one or more studies, many who for any cause are irregular in their classification and desire to make up their deficiencies, many teachers in the common or high schools, who desire more through preparation for their work will find the best instruction at low rates. </p>

<p>It is the purpose of the Summer School to cover, in each subject, in Ten Weeks, the work usually done in school or college in nine months. So it is imperative that pupils begin promptly, that no time be lost.</p> 

<p>The school will open Tuesday, June 18, 1907, at 9 a.m.</p>
<div>INSTRUCTORS</div>
<p>The Summer School faculty will be composed of the following instructors:
<list>
<item>
DOUGLAS RUMBLE, A. B., Adjunct Professor of Mathematics, Emory College, Mathematics and English.</item>
<item>NOLAN A. GOODYEAR, A. B., Principal Palmer Institute, Oxford, Ga.</item>
<item>EDWARD K. TURNER, A. B., A. M., Ph. D., Professor of Latin, Emory College, Latin and German.</item></list></p></div>
<div><head>EXPENSES</head>
<p>Board can be had in private families in Oxford at from <hi rend="bold">$10.00</hi> to <hi rend="bold">$18.00</hi> per month. The fees for tuition are: One course <hi rend="bold">$10.00</hi>; Two courses <hi rend="bold">$15.00</hi>; Three courses <hi rend="bold">$20.00</hi>. Students are advised not to attempt more than two courses, unless one or more be review. All fees are payable in advance.</p></div>
<div><head>EXAMINATIONS</head>
<p>Two regular examinations will be held: in the middle, and at the end of the term, for which no charge is made. Requests for special examinations, in order to receive consideration, must be accompanied with a fee of <hi rend="bold">$2.00</hi>.</p>
<p>
For further information address,EDWARD K. TURNER, Prin. <lb/>Emory College Summer School, <<lb/>Oxford, Georgia</p>
</div>
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>