<TEI xml:id="sister_origp1" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Letter from Gerard to his sister, an electronic edition</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Gerard, Brother</reg>
	      <sic>Brother Gerard</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2009</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2009, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
         <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <name>Jeff Galle</name>
	  <name>Mark Swails</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Letter from Gerard to his sister, Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  <!-- or 1900-1999 -->
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>10/05/2009</date>   
          <name>Hartley, Stephen></name> and <name>Rodriguez, Borinquen</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
  <body>
	<div type= "letter">
	<pb facs="sister_origp1.jpg"/>
	<head>Letter from Gerard to his sister, an electronic edition</head>
	
<opener>
Dear Sister,
</opener> 
 
<p>
I have for the first time attepted to write to you thinking that this duty must <sic>bea</sic> attented to <gap reason="illegible" unit="word"/> you but as I was told in brother William's letter which comes to hand a few days ago that you thought that I had slighted you. I now take this oppurtunity of asking your pardon and hope that you will not fail to answer this letter or I will begin to think as you did as brother is very <sic>buissy</sic> you must not wait for him to answer this letter but you must do so yourself or I will think that you do not think <sic>enoughf</sic> of me to spend the time in writing a few lines me if it is not but a half a dozen they will bea very acceptable. 
</p>
 
<p>
You <sic>mus</sic> tell all the young ladies that enquire after me that I am yet in good health but as I was not much of a ladies man when I was at home I think that you will not have to tell many of them so there is but few young ladies here but if there was a great many i would not have any time love with them as I am now very <sic>buissily</sic> engaged with my studdies which prevents me from writing you a longer or more interesting letter but you <sic>mus</sic> answer it as soon as possible and I will try and write you nmore in the mean time it is now of ten O' clock and allmost of all my time <sic>hasbeen</sic> taken up in this short litter ever
<closer><salute> believe me youre brother</salute><signed> Gerrard.</signed></closer>
</p> 
</div></body></text></TEI>