<!-- this seems pretty incomplete.  do we really want to keep it? -->

<TEI xml:id="Unknown_author_letter_September13.xml" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rng="relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Unknown author, letter, <date when="1863-09-13">September13 [1863?]</date>, an electronic edition.</title>
	<author>
	  <name type="person">
	    <choice>
	      <reg>Unknown</reg>
	      <sic>Unknown</sic>
	    </choice>
	  </name>
	</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <extent></extent>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Emory University, Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Atlanta, Georgia</pubPlace>
        <date>2009</date>
        <availability>
          <p>&#x00A9; 2009, Lewis H. Beck Center, Emory University.
  Emory University makes a claim of copyright only to original
  contributions made by the Oxford Experience Project participants.  Emory University makes no claim of copyright to the original text.  Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce, distribute, or display the contributions to this work claimed by Emory University for non-profit educational purposes, provided that this header is included in its entirety.  For further inquiries about this text's availability, please contact:
<address><addrLine>Lewis H. Beck Center</addrLine><addrLine>Emory University</addrLine><addrLine>Robert W. Woodruff Library</addrLine><addrLine>Atlanta, GA  30322-0053</addrLine><addrLine>United States of America</addrLine><addrLine>Email:  beckctr@emory.edu</addrLine></address></p>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>The Oxford Experience</title>
        <respStmt>
         <name>Adriane Ivey</name>
          <name>Jeff Galle</name>
	  <name>Mark Swails</name>
          <resp>Principal Investigators</resp>
        </respStmt>
      </seriesStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>Unknown author,letter, September13 [1863?], Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library, Emory University.</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <projectDesc>
        <p>This text was created by the Lewis H. Beck Center as a part
	of the Oxford Experience Project.  Project participants intend for this encoded text, as well as all texts produced by this project, to be made available on the web for educational, scholarly and pedagogical purposes.</p>
      </projectDesc>
      <samplingDecl>
        <p>The archival material has been transcribed and encoded.
	Paratextual elements may be provided as digital images only, with some exceptions.</p>
      </samplingDecl>
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Processing this electronic text file began by creating TIFF
images of each page using either a flatbed scanner.  Text pages were
captured in color at 300dpi.  These digital images were converted to
an electronic text file by transcription.  The text files produced
have been proofread against the original document or a JPEG image of
the original.  This proofread text file has then been encoded using
the recommendations for Level 3 of the TEI in Libraries Guidelines.
For the details of Level 3 encoding, please see the webpage for TEI
Guidelines for Best Encoding practices at
http://www.indiana.edu/~letrs/tei/.  Encoders silently replaced em
dashes with two dashes.  Page numbers and other text such as titles
displayed in brackets have been added by the encoder and do not appear
in the original text.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
      <classDecl>
        <taxonomy xml:id="lcsh">
          <bibl>
            <title>Library of Congress Subject Headings</title>
          </bibl>
        </taxonomy>
      </classDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <rs type="collection">Oxford Experience</rs>
        <rs type="language">English</rs>
        <rs type="ethnicity">Caucasian</rs>
        <rs type="form">Edited</rs>
        <rs type="genre"></rs>
        <rs type="geography">United States</rs>
        <date>1800-1899</date>  
      </creation>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="lcsh">
          <list>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
            <item></item>
          </list>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change>On <date>2009/10/06</date>   
          <name>Kevin Mauge-Lewis</name> and <name>Nicholas Cooper-Kedrick</name> and <name>Justin Johnson</name> and <name>Tiesha Cullins</name> and <name>Courtney Manning</name>
        transcribed and encoded the document.  
      </change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
<text>
  <body>
	<div type= "Letter">
	<pb facs="6081.jpg"/>
	<head> [Unknown author,letter, September13 [1863?]</head>
	<opener>
	  <name type="place">Emory College, Oxford, Ga.</name>
	  <date when="1892-02-06">Sept. 13, '63</date>

Bro Jes'
</opener>
<p>I received yours a few days since.  It offerded me much pleasure to hear from you as it has been some time since I had received a letter from you before.</p>

<p>I have again commenced the term with as bright hopes and prospects as ever.  And the farther that I advance in the dark, yet pleasant road, of science and literature and behold its <unclear reason="illegible">hidden</unclear> misteries the greater the necessity - I see of understanding then, as well as the desire of an education.  These acting as incentives serves the reader my mind content and a College life agreeable.</p>

<p>That which once was irksome has now become a pleasing duty. Nothing renders me as agreeable as that of study.  I do not intend to convey the idea that I have become over studious for there is yet <choice><sic>leasure</sic><corr> leisure</corr></choice> enough for social enjoyments with my college companions.  I refer to my companions because if my enjoyment was not with them it would be very little pleasure that it would fall to my lot to experience, for I assure you that the pleasure that I enjoy from female association is but little as it is very seldom that 

<pb facs="6082.jpg"/>

I even visit there <choice><sic>oing</sic><corr>owing</corr></choice> to two very good reasons, I say good reasons, i don't know that any thing is a good reason why a young man should not occasionaly visit the ladies yet reasons such as I have are sufficient to prevent me in a great measure: my reasons are first my own <unclear reason="illegible"><choice><orig>temidity</orig><reg>timidity</reg></choice></unclear>, which i know i indulge  to a fault, the other is that I never neglect my <choice><orig>tex</orig><reg><sic>text</sic></reg></choice> books for the enjoyment of pleasure.  My advantages for social enjoyment is better this term than it has been before this oing the <unclear reason="illegible">paychange</unclear> in my place of <unclear reason="illegible">hound</unclear>. I have left the <choice><sic>hotell</sic><corr>hotel</corr></choice> and take board in a private family where there are two very pleasant young ladies, which may be the means of improvement to me, as well as being a pleasure.</p>

<p>This term has opened under very favorable auspicies. <choice><sic>Ther</sic><corr>There</corr></choice> are now in attendance about one hundred and forty students, and still they come.</p>

	  <p>One more was aded to our number to day, <name type="place">Emory</name> is growing very popular especially with the Alabamans for the number from that quarter has increased considerably. It was thought that Dr Means leaving us would work very much against the institution, but I do not see that it has injured it at all, but on the other hand our number has been greatly increased, Taking this into consideration and also our superior College building the time is not for <unclear>asitant</unclear> when it will considered as great honor to have it to say that I am a son of Emory. Our neighboring College of Covington is also in a state of great prosperity.

<pb facs="6082.jpg"/>

I believe the day is not for distant when it will be one of the first female institutions of <name type="place">Georgia</name>.</p>

<p>Its numbers now between eighty and a hundred students, <name type="person"><choice><reg>Dr. Means</reg><sic>Dr. Means</sic></choice></name> is now at its head. His fame as an istructor will add much to the importance of the institution.</p>

<p>Politics is raging very high through this section especially in this county, Great excitement up <gap reason="pageTorn"/>
<unclear reason="illegible">licker</unclear> question.  The preminent <gap reason="pageTorn"/>
taking sides for and some against <gap reason="pageTorn"/>
are three sets of candidates out for <gap reason="pageTorn"/>
one for legislation, one against it, <gap reason="pageTorn"/>
cal issues of the day.<gap reason="pageTorn"/></p>
	  <closer> All of our <unclear>family</unclear> 
<gap reason="pageTorn"/>
then,<gap reason="pageTorn"/>
My<gap reason="pageTorn"/> from them
To Joseph 
</closer>
</div></body></text></TEI>